OSCAR SACA

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CONTACT

+1 661 993 8296



oscarsaca88@gmail.com



Austin, TX



www.oscarsaca.com

PROFILE

Versatile and creative engineer with 7 years of proven leadership and meaningful contributions to teams of varying size and scope. Passionate about going the extra mile to ensure clients are unquestionably satisfied with the product or service provided. Enthusiastic about working with a team of motivated individuals who wish to work towards the advancement of the company and its goals.

EDUCATION

BS, COMPUTING TECHNOLOGY

Brandman University 2016

BA, CRIMINAL JUSTICE

Chapman University 2012

SKILLS

HTML5

CSS3 / SCSS

JavaScript

Typescript

Angular

React

Storybook

Figma

Agile/Scrum

WORK EXPERIENCE

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Scorpion / Remote | 2021 - Current

Senior Engineer on Scorpion's new user-facing reporting platform. Collaborated with the VP of Engineering, 1 product manager, 2 designers, and 6 engineers to develop 100+ shared components for an enterprise-level application.

- Upgraded 40+ existing components to be reusable while adding additional features.
- Rewrote CSS Flexbox framework in SCSS, modernizing the code and reducing the output by over 33%.
- Assisted in creating documentation and interactive stories for all components and their respective states.

SENIOR FRONT-END PRODUCT DEVELOPER

Scorpion / Remote | 2017 - 2021

Senior front-end developer for Scorpion's internal website automation product (USC), which enabled project managers to generate client websites without a developer.

- USC contributed 7.5M in monthly recurring revenue with 2.5K clients.
- Collaborated with product managers, designers, and a team of product developers to ensure best practices for UI/UX and web accessibility.
- Lead front-end developer for the Scorpion's Advertising internal platform (CSX).
- Mentored 5 team members, enabling them to achieve professional growth and personal goals.

SENIOR WEB DEVELOPER

Scorpion | 2016 – 2017

Lead front-end developer responsible for collaborating with designers and project managers to build stunning and effective marketing websites for highest paying clients.

- Delivered 30+ projects, contributing \$172K in monthly recurring revenue.
- Set company standard for responsive design.
- Earned employee of the month award.